<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Places to Visit in Lucknow</string>
    <string name="b">Bara Imambara</string>
    <string name="baraimambara">The name refers to a shrine built by the Nawab Asaf-ud-daula in 1784, and is one of the largest buildings in Lucknow. The name ‘Bara Imambara’ is an Urdu word, wherein the word ‘Bara’ means big and ‘Imambara’ means the shrine complex. The complex includes the Asfi mosque and the Bhulbhulaiya or the Labyrinth. The Asfi mosque contains the tomb of Asaf-ud-daula, and the labyrinth is the only maze in India and supports the massive structure of the whole complex from the underground.</string>
    <string name="chotaimambara">Another congregation complex of the Shia Muslim sect, The Chota Imambara was built in 1838 by Nawab Muhammad Shah Ali. The complex also serves as the tomb for the Nawab who is buried there alongside his mother. Right outside the complex also lays the 4 storied Satkhanda, an unfinished watchtower or observatory which was supposed to have 7 stories. The Nawab wanted to make a tower as tall as the Qutab Minar and is like the Leaning Tower of Pisa in design.</string>
    <string name="britishresidency">British Residency is regarded as a National Monument and is one of the major sites of the Revolt of 1857 and the historic battle known as the Seige of Lucknow. The site was the residence of the British Resident General which was stormed during the battle. The structure though in ruins after the battle has still been preserved till date with the bullet grazed walls and is surrounded by gardens which attract a great number of tourist crowd.</string>
    <string name="constantiahouse">The site formerly known as the Constantia House is now housed by the La Martinière College. The building is located on a terraced location which was a lake at some point. The architecture is mixed style that combines various techniques of Italian architecture. The college is one of the only educational institutions to receive a battle honor due to its role during the Seige of Lucknow.</string>
    <string name="chattarmanzil">The name Chattar Manzil literally means the Umbrella Palace and was the residence to the Nawabs of Awadh and their successors. The palace was constructed in the 1780’s and became one of the major strongholds of the revolutionaries during the 1857 uprising. The architectural style of the original building was a cross between Indo-European styles and was later restored by the British according to their preferences.</string>
    <string name="rumi">Also known by the name, Turkish Gate, the Rumi Darwaza was built in 1784 by the Nawab Asaf-ud-daula. The monument is a massive gateway which is one of the best specimens of Awadhi Style architecture. The monument’s grandness in design is often compared to that of Rome and the Ottoman Empire and marks the entrance to the old city of Lucknow. </string>
    <string name="balaji">Balaji Temple in Lucknow is a newly-constructed shrine, built on the pattern of the famous Tirupati Balaji Temple in south India. Covering a large area of 27,000 sq ft, the grand architecture is the result of the hard work of well-trained artisans and experts from south India. The moment you’ll step inside, you’ll see Navagrah or nine planetary gods one side while in the main temple premises, there are beautifully carved idols of Lord Venketeshwar, Goddess Andal, Goddess Padmavathi and Lord Hanuman. People from all across the city visit the Balaji Temple to offer their prayers and also to witness its grandeur.</string>
    <string name="chandrika">Chandrika Devi Temple is situated on the bank of river Gomti  at north-west of National Highway No.24 (Lucknow-Sitapur Road) in Kathvara village, near Lucknow City, UP,India. This  300 years old temple is well known for the deity Chandrika Devi - a form of Goddess Durga. Located in a natural environment encircled by river Gomti at north,west and south side, it is around 28 Kms. away from the main city of Lucknow. It is about 45 Kms. away from Lucknow Airport. This place and nearby areas have relevance and religious significance since the time of the Ramayana. It is also called Mahi Sagar Teerth. There is mention of this temple in Skand and Karma Puran -the holy books. </string>
    <string name="aliganjhanuman">Based on the temple history, Begum Rabiya of the Nawab Mohammed Ali Shah established this temple in the Lucknow. Once she had a dream that  there is a grand statue of Lord Hanuman lying near a garden and that she should  dig it out and kept in a temple. After she was blessed with a child, the Nawab thereafter immediately started excavating that place. To his utter surprise he found a statue of Lord Hanuman there. Nawab ordered that the statue be got established in a temple near Bara Imambara.  While the statue was being taken, the elephant carrying it, stopped and sat down at a place in Aliganj. A number of efforts to stand up the elephant became futile.  On the advice of a  saint of  the area, Begum ordered to establish the Lord  Hanuman at that same place.  A  temple was got constructed at this place and nearby plot of land was given for the upkeep of temple. This temple is now called new Hanuman Temple of Aliganj in Lucknow.The Famous ‘Bara Mangal’  festival of Lucknow is held in Lucknow each year in Jeth month and is associated mainly with this ancient temple.</string>
    <string name="sankat">The temple of the Lord  Hanuman is one of the most reversed and famous temples in the Lucknow. The main features of the temple is that, many devotees write letters to Lord Hanuman elaborating their problems and it is believed that  all such letters are read before the Lord by the priests. It is said that Lord Hanuman always shower the blessings on the devotees.This temple was established by Baba Neeb Karauri near the old bridge.It is said that during the floods of 1960 the temple was swept away but the statue of Lord remained there intact. Recently, a new temple was got constructed near the new bridge on January 26, 1967. </string>
    <string name="sheetla">The Sheetala Devi Temple in Mehandiganj Mohalla is one of the ancient and famous temples for Devi in the Lucknow. It is said that the  temple was destroyed by the  some unknown intruders  and it was only after centuries that a  prominent businessman  first located the idol of Devi in the water of a nearby pond. After that the temple was reconstructed. While entering into the temple , there is a satute of the lion before the temple and two lions on the door of the temple. Raja Tikait Rai, the then  Diwan of Nawab,  got constructed  this temple  and also  a very large pond  with a number of down stairs which is at present called “Tikait Rai ka Talab’. The temple witnesses each year the famous  Aathon Ka Mela  of Lucknow which is held on/after the Holi festival each year. The fare  is visited by people of Lucknow and adjoining area in a large number. During this period temple is well decorated and Goddess is offered Puri, Halwa, chana, clove and betel nuts.On the day of Sheetal Ashtami, Goddess is worshiped duly and offered baasi (stale) prasad.</string>
    <string name="setu"></string>
    <string name="surya">This age-old Temple is located near Daliganj Bridge and close to Lucknow Planetarium. The Surya Dev’s idol is imagined to be of decades old. The Temple is very close to the Suraj Kund, the holy water pond. There is a popular belief that the pond’s water has a medicinal significance. During ‘Kartik Snan’, a huge crowd accumulates here to visit the mela adjacent to the Temple and pond.</string>
    <string name="shiva">This is another famous Shiva Temple located on the northern side of Bakshi Ka Talab on Sitapur Road, adjoining Chandrika Devi Temple. This antique Temple was created by Munshi Tripur Chand Bakshi. This historic Temple was constructed almost 300 years back during the reign of Nawab Amajad Ali Shah.</string>
    <string name="mann">This Temple is exactly located in between Hasanganj and Daliganj area of Lucknow. It has been heard that whenever the profound believers have sought any of their desires in this Temple, their wish has been definitely fulfilled. The Temple stays open from 5 am to 12 pm and from 4 pm to 9 pm. Visitors are allowed to stay inside for 30 minutes to 1 hour.</string>
    <string name="bhoot">Just 5 kilometres away from Hazratganj, this Temple is situated in Indiranagar, Lucknow on main Faizabad Road. Lucknow’s famous Bhoot Nath Market has emerged on that area surrounding the Hanuman Temple. The key attraction of this Temple is the statue of Lord Shiva and Parvati Devi.</string>
</resources>
